<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Topic Modeling on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</title>
    <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/topic-modeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Topic Modeling on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/topic-modeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TutVis: A Tool to Visualize Tutorials - Topic Modeling(LDA), Random Forest, Angular js</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-tutvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-tutvis/</guid>
      <description>Online text and video tutorials are among the most popular and heavily used resources for learning feature-rich software applications (e.g., Photoshop, Weka, AutoCAD, Fusion 360). However, when searching, users can find it difficult to assess whether a tutorial is designed for their level of expertise. TutVis stands for tutorial visualization, which is a Photoshop tutorial browsing system that provides auto-generated information to assist users in the tutorial searching and selection. The provided information is as follows: difficulty level (advanced/beginner), topics covered, length, text complexity, command usage ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Topic Extraction from Documents - LDA, Top2Vec</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-topic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-topic/</guid>
      <description>The objective is to develop an automated tool, which can find out topics from any article. Different topic modeling techniques are investigated for this topic extraction task. For the investigation, yahoo answer dataset has been chosen. The dataset has ~1.5M question-answer pairs. Only 60,000 samples has been randomly chosen from the data. From the selected data, only the answers are used to train the models. The models are trained using LDA and Top2Vec.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>