<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regression on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</title>
    <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/regression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regression on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/regression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Earthquake Prediction Dashboard - Spark, Tableau, MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-earthquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-earthquake/</guid>
      <description>The objective is to report the prediction of the earthquake from the historical data. A machine learning model is trained with historical data of the world related to earthquakes from 1965-2016. The data includes geographical location and magnitude of the earthquakes (23.5k samples). The model predicts earthquake magnitude for the year of 2017. Finally, a dashboard is created to visualize the prediction in addition to the historical analysis on the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Prediction - Bidirectional LSTM</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-weather/</guid>
      <description>This project predicts weather (i.e., min-max temperature) from historical data. The dataset includes hourly inputs of pressure, humidity, temperature, wind speed, and wind direction of 36 cities from the year 2012 to 2017. From the dataset preprocessing is done to engineer attributes to predict min and max temperature of Toronto. Data from 2012-2016 is used as the training dataset, while the attempt is to predict the min and max temp of 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Food Preparation Time (SkipTheDishes) - Doc2Vec</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-food/</guid>
      <description>The objective is to predict food preparation time from ordered food items and quantity. This is a data challenge arranged by SkipTheDishes, Canada&amp;rsquo;s leading and largest food delivery company. The data includes upto 10 ordered food items along with the quantity. There are 20 features and 80,000 samples in the data. The goal is to predict food preparation time.
 Doc2Vec has been applied to vectorize food item names and feature engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Price Prediction - Regression</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-houseprice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-houseprice/</guid>
      <description>The objecive of this project is to predict house price from different features. The dataset includes 1460 instances and 80 features. The following algorithms are applied as on selected features from the data:
Applied Algorithms:  Linear Regression  Decision Tree  SVM  Random Forest  AdaBoost  GradientBoost  XGBoost  Feature selection is performed using Parson Correlation.  Feature imputation, encoding, and scaling is performed.  The best performance achieved is R-square = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>