<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Django on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</title>
    <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/django/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Django on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Loan Enquiry - ANN, Django</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-loan/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this project is to predict if a customer will get a loan given applicant income, loan amount, loan amount term, credit history, education status, self-employment status, property area, etc. A model is trained using the training data on previous customers&amp;rsquo; loan approval history. A web service is created, which runs the trained model in the background. The service presents an interface through which any user can request to get an automated decision/prediction (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DynamicViz: Change data in real time. - Tableau, Django, REST API</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-dynamicviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-dynamicviz/</guid>
      <description>Modify data from Tableau dashboard   The objective of this project is to develop a dynamic dashboard in Tableau which can update the data source. The dataset for this visualization includes wheat consumption (domestic, fsi, feed dom., etc) in Canada over 20 years timeline.
 XAMPP is used to host the data in a local server. The data is fetched from the local server into Tableau. The Tableau dashboard presents a crosstab and a line chart of the time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>