<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</title>
    <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind Reader - A pdf reader designed for blinds - Android, Java</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-blindreader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-blindreader/</guid>
      <description>A pdf reader that allows a blind person to read documents. The concept is to use the haptic touch on the screen and speak aloud the word on tap. This system provides some smart features e.g., dynamic scrolling, line checking and vibration notification for the line break. The system is built on the Android platform. The smart feature - dynamic scrolling leverages the phone gyroscope reading and can detect tilt. Based on the tilt angle it triggers the scrolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eExpense: A smart approach to track everyday expenses - Android, Java, Tesseract-OCR</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-eexpense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-eexpense/</guid>
      <description>eExpense is a smart system that keeps track of everyday expenses. Some of the key functionalities of this app are automatically detecting expenses from text messages, automatically taking input from the receipts, creating a balance sheet, showing history in the calendar view.  The system is built on the Android platform.  The input from receipts is taken using Tesseract OCR (Optical Character Recognition) engine.  Publication Source: Check the publication</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>