<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tableau on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</title>
    <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/tableau/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tableau on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/tableau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Earthquake Prediction Dashboard - Spark, Tableau</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-earthquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-earthquake/</guid>
      <description>The objective is to report the prediction of the earthquake from the historical data. A machine learning model is trained with historical data of the world related to earthquakes from 1965-2016. The data includes geographical location and magnitude of the earthquakes (23.5k samples). The model predicts earthquake magnitude for the year of 2017. Finally, a dashboard is created to visualize the prediction in addition to the historical analysis on the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID 19 USA Dashboard - Tableau</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-usdashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-usdashboard/</guid>
      <description>An interactive visualization dashboard including different states&amp;rsquo; (of USA) confirmed cases and the number of deaths. The visualization presents different calculations such as top N states (i.e., N can be changed from the dashboard) with total confirmed cases and deaths, new cases and deaths; case fatality rates (CFR) on time series data collected from https://github.com/nytimes/covid-19-data. The interactive dashboard is created using Tableau Desktop. Different pie charts, maps, line charts, and stack bars are used in this visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID 19 World Visualization Dashboard - Tableau</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-worlddashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-worlddashboard/</guid>
      <description>The dashboard presents an interactive visualization of the latest COVID-19 updates. It includes the trend line of the time series data, geographic map, cumulative &amp;amp; newly confirmed, active, death, and recovered cases. It also presents a calculation on Case Fatality Rate (CFR), confirmed &amp;amp; death cases in 100,000. The regular update is taken from https://github.com/datasets/covid-19. Data is preprocessed using Tableau prep builder. Tableau is used for the visualization. In this visualization, users can drill down to the country to see region-specific details (new cases and trends) and also overall comparisons among different regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Dashboard on Canadian Wheat Production - Tableau, D3 js, Chart js, Angular js</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-wheatproduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-wheatproduction/</guid>
      <description>Dashboard presenting analysis on Wheat   The purpose of this project is to gain insights into the agricultural market data of different commodities, e.g., Wheat, Corn, Barley, Oats etc. and present them in a dashboard. The data includes different attributes such as consumption, production, import, export, stocks, yield of the commodities. The data reports attributes on 125 countries and over 20 years timeline.
 The UI supports responsive layouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DynamicViz: Change data in real time. - Tableau, Django, REST API</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-dynamicviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-dynamicviz/</guid>
      <description>Modify data from Tableau dashboard   The objective of this project is to develop a dynamic dashboard in Tableau which can update the data source. The dataset for this visualization includes wheat consumption (domestic, fsi, feed dom., etc) in Canada over 20 years timeline.
 XAMPP is used to host the data in a local server. The data is fetched from the local server into Tableau. The Tableau dashboard presents a crosstab and a line chart of the time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>