<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Angular on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</title>
    <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/angular/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Angular on Shahed Anzarus Sabab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/tags/angular/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TutVis: A Tool to Visualize Tutorials - Topic Modeling(LDA), Random Forest, Angular js</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-tutvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-tutvis/</guid>
      <description>Online text and video tutorials are among the most popular and heavily used resources for learning feature-rich software applications (e.g., Photoshop, Weka, AutoCAD, Fusion 360). However, when searching, users can find it difficult to assess whether a tutorial is designed for their level of expertise. TutVis stands for tutorial visualization, which is a Photoshop tutorial browsing system that provides auto-generated information to assist users in the tutorial searching and selection. The provided information is as follows: difficulty level (advanced/beginner), topics covered, length, text complexity, command usage ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Dashboard on Canadian Wheat Production - Tableau, D3 js, Chart js, Angular js</title>
      <link>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-wheatproduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahedsabab.github.io/shahed_portfolio/post/project-wheatproduction/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project is to gain insights into the agricultural market data of different commodities, e.g., Wheat, Corn, Barley, Oats etc. and present them in a dashboard. The data includes different attributes such as consumption, production, import, export, stocks, yield of the commodities. The data reports attributes on 125 countries and over 20 years timeline.
 The UI supports responsive layouts. For developing the visualizations, PSD Grain Data_small.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>